<sect1 id="requirements" xreflabel="Bulletin Board Requirements">
<title>Bulletin Board Requirements</title>

<authorblurb><para>
By <ulink url="mailto:akk@arsdigita.com">Anukul Kapoor</ulink>, <ulink url="mailto:psu@arsdigita.com">Pete Su</ulink> and <ulink url="mailto:mthomas@arsdigita.com">Mark Thomas</ulink> 
</para></authorblurb>

<sect2 id="requirements-intro">
<title>Introduction</title>


<para>This document outlines necessary functionality and behavior of the new ACS
4.0 Bulletin Board system (herein referred to as bboard).</para>

<para>Our intent (as of 8/2000) is to start with a simple implementation that
can accomodate future advanced functionality. As a result, these requirements
may not prescribe functionality present in the ACS 3.4 bboard system. We are
using the uslaw-bboard module as inspiration for a lightweight
implementation.</para>

<para>Futhermore, this document is conservative in attempting to describe the
ultimate framework for modular web based messaging. We hope such an
architecture may well be born out of iterative process when designing this
system. However, the scope is being primarily limited to functional
requirements.</para>

<para>The <link linkend="requirements-future">future requirements</link> should inform the design process if
not initially implemented.</para>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="requirements-vision">
<title>Vision Statement</title>


<para>An electronic bulletin board system is one of the simplest and most
effective forms of collaboration between people separated in space and time.
Bboards provide a centralized and shared venue for discussion that save
communication costs over ad-hoc mechanisms (like arbitrary email lists).
Since messages are organized by topic as well as temporally, bboard can
provide lightweight interfaces for rapidly navigating to interesting
messages. This low barrier to participation encourages spontaneous
collaboration between disperse parties in the community.</para>

<para>The bboard system also serves as a useful archive and ad-hoc knowledge
management tool by virtue of its persistence, light weight organizational
structure, and flexible browse and search facilities. This sort of knowledge
base can be easily leveraged to provide long term pedagogical value as well
as aid in future problem solving.</para>

<para>When integrated with an email system, bboards radically improve email
based collaboration. Email notifications can encourage continuous awareness
of community issues. Email based reply functionality further lowers the
barrier to participation, encouraging more Interaction around the
Transaction&trade;.</para>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="requirements-system-overview">
<title>System/Application Overview</title>


<para>The bboard system allows users to browse, read, and post messages
organized into forums. Messages consist of short text messages with optional
attachments such as image files or html documents. Messages are organized
into threads when users reply to each other, maintaining the temporal flow of
a particular discussion.</para>

<para>Forums are contexts for discussion relating to a particular domain of
interest. Examples include the photo.net Q&amp;A forum, the ArsDigita Web/DB
forum, and the away.com discussion forum. Messages within a particular forum
can optionally be tagged as being in certain categories to assist searching
and navigation. Forums are always created in the context of a subsite.</para>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="requirements-use-cases">
<title>IV. Use-cases and User Scenarios</title>


<para><emphasis role="strong">Administrator</emphasis>: Phillis Goodsport is a world famous
lithographer who wants to share her knowledge about lithography and encourage
interaction between a community of lithographers on her new site litho.net.
Although she likes the idea of a broad forum for general lithography
discussion, she wants browsing to be tractable when traffic increases. If
quality goes down, she&#39;d like to dedicate one of her minions to
moderating traffic to maintain her high standards.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">Casual browser and poster</emphasis>: Joe Schmoe goes to photo.net
for the first time and wants to ask what zoom lens to buy. He needs to find
the appropriate category/topic to post his message.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">Compulsive reader and expert poster</emphasis>: Jane Developer is a
web development guru and wants to keep up with as much of the traffic on the
web/db forum as possible. She wants to become aware of posts that might
become relevant to her in the future as well as help out folks who have
problems she knows how to solve. Since Jane is on lots of developer mailing
lists, her preferred form of interaction is via email.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">Moderator</emphasis>: Dave Balderdash is a chatter.net moderator and
wants to delete redundant or useless posts. He&#39;s short on time, so he
wants a quick interface for rejecting and approving posts.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">Targeted researcher</emphasis>: Ted Stetson is an ACS developer who
remembers someone mentioning something about his Oracle problem on a bboard.
He wants to find records of similar problems and any related solutions.</para>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="requirements-links">
<title>Related Links</title>


<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><xref linkend="design"/></para></listitem>

<listitem><para>Test Plan (not available)</para></listitem>

<listitem><para><ulink url="http://www.arsdigita.com/general-comments/view-one?comment_id=28646&amp;item=BBoard%20module">
notes on USLaw-BBoard implementation</ulink></para></listitem>

<listitem><para><ulink url="/doc/subsites-requirements.html">Subcommunities</ulink></para></listitem>

<listitem><para><ulink url="http://www.arsdigita.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0003ye">Karl&#39;s
thoughts on bboard redesign</ulink></para></listitem>

<listitem><para><ulink url="http://www.arsdigita.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0007ew">Adam
Farkas&#39;s web/db thread on bboard improvements</ulink></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="requirements-ui">
<title>Requirements: User Interface</title>

<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="strong">10.10 End User Basics</emphasis></para>

<blockquote>
<para><emphasis role="strong">10.10.10</emphasis> The bboard system must provide mechanism for
users to effectively choose which messages to read within a forum. Bboard
must provide an overview interface to enable users to find messages of
interest or relevant to them. This overview should provide the user with
cursory information to facilitate quick scanning and meaningful evaluation of
message contents.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.10.15</emphasis> The full text of bboard messages should be
searchable by user queries.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.10.20</emphasis> <emphasis role="strong">[unimplemented]</emphasis> Bboard
should consistently provide a mechanism to limit or sort displayed posts by
categories, posters, and date range as well as to perform a text search.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.10.30</emphasis> <emphasis role="strong">[unimplemented]</emphasis> Most
users primarily want to browse and read new posts or replies since their last
visit. The bboard interface must allow users to ignore messages they&#39;ve
already read.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.10.40</emphasis> <emphasis role="strong">[unimplemented]</emphasis> Users
should be able to search within and limit scope to messages they have already
read as well as messages they have not read at all.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.10.50</emphasis> Users must be able to easily post new messages
to a bboard, or reply to existing messages they have come across. When
replying, users must be presenting with enough context to assist their
composition.</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="strong">10.20 Email Integration</emphasis></para>

<blockquote>
<para><emphasis role="strong">10.20.10</emphasis> Users can register for email notification of new
messages in a particular forums.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.20.13</emphasis> Users can register for email notifications on a
particular thread.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.20.16</emphasis> Users can register for email notifications on a
particular category.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.20.20</emphasis> <emphasis role="strong">[unimplemented]</emphasis>
Notifications can be sent as each message arrives or in an organized digest
form over a configurable time period.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.20.30</emphasis> Individual messages will have appropriate RFC
822 headers to enable threading in the mail client.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.20.40</emphasis> <emphasis role="strong">[unimplemented]</emphasis> Email
from the alert system should be tagged in the header with the site and forum
name to enable easy filtering in mail clients. Well, as easy as the mail
clients make it anyway.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.20.50</emphasis> <emphasis role="strong">[unimplemented]</emphasis> If the
user requests it, email generated should use MIME encoding to deliver
attachements and appropriately encode HTML. Otherwise plain text emails
should be augmented with URLs and styling cues in place of rich content.</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="strong">10.30 Administrative Requirements</emphasis></para>

<blockquote>
<para><emphasis role="strong">10.30.10</emphasis> The bboard system must support a flexible
presentation layer that allows custom layout of bboard content.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.30.15</emphasis> Publishers should have the option of displaying
discussions in a flat linear fashion or in an indented threaded view.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.30.20</emphasis> Parties with administrative privileges on a
particular subsite can create, delete, and edit forums scoped to that
subsite.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.30.30</emphasis> Forums can be designated moderated in which case
parties with sufficient privileges must approve messages before they are
displayed generally.</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="strong">10.40 Access Control Requirements</emphasis></para>

<blockquote>
<para>Objects must be structured to allow the flexible configuration and assignment
of the following privileges: </para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.40.10</emphasis> Reading forums</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.40.20</emphasis> Reading messages</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.40.30</emphasis> Posting new messages</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.40.50</emphasis> Approving and rejecting posted messages (for
moderated groups)</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.40.60</emphasis> Managing the forum (editing title and
description, determining moderation and restriction policies, granting
approval privileges to others, banning users)</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">10.40.70</emphasis> Managing categories (editing, deleting,
combining categories)</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="requirements-datamodel">
<title>Requirements: Data-model</title>

<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="strong">20.10 Messages</emphasis></para>

<blockquote>
<para><emphasis role="strong">20.10.10</emphasis> Messages are the basic units of the bboard
module. The bboard system will provide a repository to store text
messages.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">20.10.20</emphasis> Messages will be tagged as having HTML, plain
text, or preformatted text in their body.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">20.10.30</emphasis> Messages will have a brief plain text subject
line.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">20.10.40</emphasis> Messages will be related to their creating
user.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">20.10.50</emphasis> Messages may optionally have binary
attachments.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">20.10.60</emphasis> The bboard system must store relations between
messages and their replies to enable threaded views.</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="strong">20.20 Forums</emphasis></para>

<blockquote>
<para><emphasis role="strong">20.20.10</emphasis> Forums are the main administrative units of the
bboard system. Forums are containers to which messages uniquely belong.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">20.20.20</emphasis> Forums must have a brief text descriptions and
optionally a longer description called a charter.</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="strong">20.30 Categories</emphasis></para>

<blockquote>
<para><emphasis role="strong">20.30.10</emphasis> There must be a mechanism for intra-forum
categorization to facilitate filter, searching, and tractability.</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="requirements-api">
<title>Requirements: API</title>


<para><emphasis>No requirements in this section are met by the current
implementation.</emphasis></para> 

<para>Since bboard is primarily an end user application any exposed APIs will
come out of the design rather than nailed down requirements from the start.
Stay tuned.</para>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="requirements-future">
<title>Possible Future Requirements</title>

<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10 In no particular order</emphasis></para>

<blockquote>
<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.10</emphasis> bboard should provide a framework for extending
the generic messaging repository with meta-data and in tandem extending the
user interface to take advantage of this meta-data. This would let developers
properly layer functionality such as geo-spatial messaging and slashdot style
scoring. This is actually provided via ACS messaging and the ACS Object
system.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.20</emphasis> bboard should support replying to and
initiating threads from email. Administrative email list functionality should
be developed or integrated.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.30</emphasis> Bboard should let users register interests
(categories, certain users, keywords) for the purpose of filtering and
sorting message displays.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.40</emphasis> Users should have the option of enabling spell
checking on their posts. A framework for filtering (removing bad words,
promoting text URLs to html links, auto detecting HTML vs. plain text, etc.,)
should exist.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.50</emphasis> Allow users to configure how big the textareas
editing widgets they get are.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.60</emphasis> Moderators should be given the <emphasis>option</emphasis>
of making notes on a given discussion that appear prominently in the
discussion display.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.70</emphasis> Moderators should be able to set posts to
expire at a configurable time in the future.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.80</emphasis> Mega bonus points: an nntp gateway to bboards
for access from standard news clients.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.90</emphasis> The bboard system should be able to take
advantage of a caching system that stores the results of database queries for
optimal scalability.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.100</emphasis> Publishers should have the option of allowing
users to edit various parts of messages after they are posted (e.g. the text
body, the subject, the text presentaiton style etc.,)</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.110</emphasis> A user interface should allow administrators
to easily categorize or recategorize existing messages.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.120</emphasis> Publishers should be able to classify users
based on their forum contributions and appropriately target them for email,
promotions, etc.,</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.130</emphasis> Explicit permissions for posting new messages
vs. posting replies.</para>

<para><emphasis role="strong">40.10.140</emphasis> Explicit permissions for posting
attachments.</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="strong">40.20 Performance requirements</emphasis></para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="requirements-rev-history">
<title>Revision History</title>


 
<informaltable>
<tgroup cols="4">

<thead>
<row role="revisiontop">
<entry>Document Revision #</entry>
<entry>Action Taken, Notes</entry>
<entry>When?</entry>
<entry>By Whom?</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>

<row role="revisionbody">
<entry>0.2</entry>
<entry>Revision: More standard style, more detailed requirements.</entry>
<entry>08/24/2000</entry>
<entry>Anukul Kapoor</entry>
</row>


<row>
<entry>0.1</entry>
<entry>Creation</entry>
<entry>08/23/2000</entry>
<entry>Anukul Kapoor</entry>
</row>

</tbody>
</tgroup>
</informaltable>

</sect2>

</sect1>

